<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>iotku's Blag (irl-stuff)</title><link>http://iotku.pw</link><description>Random stuff from the shallow mind of iotku</description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 08:16:12 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title><link>http://iotku.pw/posts/happy-thanksgiving.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Time flies fast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In what seems like hardly any time it's already the end of November. What do I have to show for it? As far as speedgaming goes I've made a few strides in running Super Mario 64, mainly getting a time under 20 minutes for 16 star and hit my 1st year mark of speedrunning. I don't plan on doing 16 star anymore outside of races because I figured out I don't really enjoy it anymore. 16 Star is incredibly repetitive, small mistakes count (even at the level I'm at which is far from optimal) and BLJs, while a neat gimmick, are annoying to mess up and sometimes don't cooperate wasting a bunch of time for no good reason (It's not my fault!.... that much).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for real life (Oh how boring...), things have been pretty uneventful for the last year, I've been out of college stuff and done basically nothing.
It's amazing how easy it is to be unproductive!
I hope to fix that in 2014 and better organize my time so I can keep from getting too stupid, while leaving room for games and actually having a life.
Some days I struggle to do anything out of what would seem to be pure laziness; that needs to stop if I want to finish college, stay reasonably smart, and avoid depression as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope for the best in my coming year, best of luck to whoever is reading this as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you've gotten this far (or skipped the block of text... cheater!) I'm going to put up ways to contact me in the navigation bar pretty soon in case someone wants to find me :p. Until then you can contact me on twitter @iotku&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>speedrunning</category><category>irl-stuff</category><guid>http://iotku.pw/posts/happy-thanksgiving.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 23:43:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>